Guide to the Harris Masterson I papers,1860-1942, bulk 1880-1920 MS 468
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Judge Harris Masterson I Papers
1860-1942, bulk 1880-1920
bulk
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Masterson, Harris, Judge
MS 468
187.5 Linear Feet (282 boxes)
Judge Harris Masterson's papers relate almost exclusively to his legal practice and real estate dealings after he moved from Brazoria County, Texas, to Houston, dating from 1860-1942, bulk 1880-1920.
Biographical / Historical
Judge Harris Masterson, the youngest son of Thomas Gilbert and Christina Masterson, was born in Brazoria County on June 30, 1856. His father, a lawyer, judge, and large landowner in Brazoria County, migrated to Texas from Nashville, Tennessee. His mother also studied law and came from Tennessee where her grandfather had been a prominent judge and governor.Harris and all five of his brothers received their legal education from her. Of the six, four entered into active legal practice, and all of the them served as judges at one time during their careers.
Harris Masterson began his legal career in Brazoria County. Although not much is known about Masterson's early career in Brazoria or his terms as judge, it seems from papers and correspondence in the collection that he became involved in land litigation early in his career. This emphasis began with his interests in his father's large holdings in Brazoria County. In June 1880, Harris Masterson married Sallie Stewart Turner, by whom he had five children, of whom only three lived beyond infancy. A short time after his wife's death in January of 1894, the Judge moved his legal practice to Houston.
From the extensive correspondence and numerous deeds in these papers, it seems Masterson dealt largely with land litigation and investments in Harris and surrounding counties, including Brazoria, Firt Bend, Galveston, Hardin, and Jefferson Counties. His land interests extended into several East Texas and Louisiana lumber companies. Since he owned so much coastal land, Spindletop and the discovery of oil opened a new field of business for Masterson. He joined with other prominent landowners in the coastal area to form small oil companies for drilling. He also made a great deal of money by leasing out his land for drilling. He became a member of the Hogg-Swayne syndicate participating in and contributing to their numerous drilling operations, as well as independently drilling with Frank Andrews and Joseph S. Cullinan. Most of the oil drilled on Masterson's land was sold to the Gulf Oil & Pipeline Company, the Sun Pipeline Company, and other large oil companies.
Masterson set up several land corporations with his brother A.R. Masterson and son Neill. Two of these were the Texas Town Lot & Improvement Company and the Houston Town Lot & Improvement Company. Although these companies on occasion contracted to build houses on the land they sold, their primary function was to buy large tracts of land and break them into smaller lots. Much of this land was sold to what would today be called the middle and lower class people of Houston. These sales then were usually financed by Harris Masterson so that in case of default, the land reverted back to the Mastersons. Through one of these companies Masterson apparently acquired some land which the owners had been unwilling to sell to the newly founded Rice Institute.
Masterson also speculated in land in Cameron County and other parts of the Rio Grande Valley which only needed irrigation to become agriculturally productive. Not coincidentally, he also bought stock in various irrigation companies. Among these were the Harlingen Land & Water Company and the La Feria Land & Water Company. Although these companies were badly mismanaged by the local operators and eventually went bankrupt, they seemed to have opened up the speculation and search for water to make this area productive. Other investments for which there are records in these papers include coal mines in West Texas, local railroads, sugar crops, cattle and ranching.
Judge Harris Masterson was a shrewd businessman who kept his wealth spread across his various investments. His employed the services of a secretary as well as his son Neill and son-in-law Elliott Cage to help him look after and protect his investments. Neill Masterson continued to care for the investments after the death of Judge Masterson in July 1900.
Source: "The Masterson Family Papers", The Flyleaf, Vol. 24, No. 3, October 1974. Friends of Fondren Library, Rice University, Houston TX. By Beth Wray, Manuscript Curator, Woodson Research Center.
Scope and Contents
Judge Masterson's papers relate almost exclusively to his legal practice and real estate dealings after he moved from Brazoria County, Texas, to Houston, dating from 1860-1942, bulk 1880-1920. He dealt primarily with land litigation and investments in Harris and surrounding counties, including Brazoria, Fort Bend, Galveston, Hardin, and Jefferson Counties. Other investments for which there are records in these papers include coal mines in West Texas, local railroads, sugar crops, cattle and ranching. Business cycles and the style of land and oil deals of the day are presented very well in the correspondence. Family correspondence also reveals Masterson's willingness to employ his own numerous nephews and generally to help people in his employ. The papers dating from Judge Masterson's death in July 1900 were created or maintained by Masterson's son Neill.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Masterson papers were donated to the Fondren Library by the Mastersons in 1957.
Index Terms
Subjects
Courts; Real estate business; Lawyers -- Texas; Law and legislation; Business
Document Types
letters (correspondence); financial records; Maps
Places
Texas -- Houston; Texas
Subjects (Persons)
Masterson, Harris, Judge; Masterson, Harris, Judge
- Series I: Bank Accounts, 1887-1942 (Boxes 1-9)
  Scope and Contents note
  Bank statements, correspondence, check stubs, receipts, arranged by bank name and then chronologically.
  - Adoue Lobit cancelled checks, 1887-1891; Houston National Exchange Bank checks stubs, 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adoue Lobit bank statements, 11-20-1885—12-1892 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adoue Lobit bank statements, 1-1893—8-1900 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adoue Lobit correspondence, 2-15-1886—3-17-1914; Adoue Lobit check registers (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - First National Bank of Houston check stubs, 1898-1904, and account books/check registers, 1898-1914 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - First National Bank of Houston bank statements, deposits, drafts, 1898-1919 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - First National Bank of Houston deposit slips, 1900-1920; correspondence with bank, 8-1904—7-1914; Deposit slips, 1915-1920 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - W.O. Ellis Co., Bankers, Houston cancelled checks, 1889-1890 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Alvin Exchange National Bank, Alvin, TX, cancelled checks, bank books, deposits, 1893-1897 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Planters Merchants National Bank, Houston, TX cancelled checks, deposits, 1890-1896 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - High Emprise, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - T.W. House, Banker, Houston, TX cancelled checks, bank books, 1897, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - W.O. Ellis Co., Bankers, bank books, 1889-1890 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Smith Bros., Brazoria, TX check stubs, 1884-1886; National Bank of Commerce bank book, 1912; Houston National Exchange Bank bank book, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bank of Angleton, Angleton, TX cancelled checks, deposits, 1987-1901 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Union National Bank cancelled checks, 1917; Velasco National Bank, Velasco, TX check stubs, 1894-1895; unknown banks check stubs, 1892-1896, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - First National Bank of Houston and Commonwealth National Bank check stubs and bank books for HM, Mrs. HM, P. Harvey; checks and bank statements from various banks—Velasco, 1892-1897, Smith Bros.—1884-1885, Planters State Bank—1917-1920, Harlingen State Bank—1916-1918, Seaboard National Bank, NY—1911 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Velasco National Bank correspondence and bank statements, 1894-1897 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Planters Mechanics National Bank statements and correspondence, 1889-1896, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - W.O. Ellis Co., Bankers statements, deposits, correspondence, 1889 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Alvin Exchange Bank statements, correspondence, 1894-1899 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - T.W. House, Banker, deposit receipts, statements, 1887-1898 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bank of Angleton statements, deposits, correspondence, 1897-1901 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bank statements, cancelled checks: Houston National Exchange Bank, 1910-1919; Gulf National Bank, 1903-1904; South Texas National Bank, 1895-1912; Misc. banks, 1887-1917 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Summary of all bank accounts, 1885 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - First National Bank statements for Mrs. H.B. Masterson, 8-6-1924—1-1925 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - First National Bank statements, 1920-1928, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Misc. bills and statements, 1910-1942 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - First National Bank check stubs, 1916-1922 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - First National Bank cancelled checks for: Mrs. H.B. Masterson, 1924-1925; N.T. Masterson, 1909-1912; H.B. Masterson, 1920-1928/ Gulf National Bank and First National Bank, Beaumont, TX bank books and cancelled checks for H.A. Perry, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - First National Bank of Houston checks stubs and deposits, 1914-1941 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series II: Business Interests, 1884-1920 (Boxes 10- 58)
  Financial records, legal documents, and correspondence related to specific companies and businesses which appear in alphabetical order by the name of the business.
  - Cameron County, TX Irrigation District #1 bond correspondence, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cameron County, TX (Harlingen), Lon C. Hill, Jr. corresp., 1913-1916 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Cameron County, TX (Harlingen), Lon C. Hill, Jr. corresp., 1916 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Cameron County, TX: abstract of property conveyed by Lon C. Hill for deeds of trust and to the Harlingen Land and Water Co., 1913 [1915] (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Cameron County, TX: judgment against and abstracts of land of Harlingen Land and Water Co., 1905 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cameron County, TX: release from deed of trust and judgment lien by H. Masterson to John H. Brooks, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Cameron County, TX: option to purchase townsite property extended to Ross L. Clark by H. Masterson, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Cameron County, TX: release from deed of trust on property to Lon C. Hill by Rio Grande Canal Co., 1914 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Cameron County, TX: partial release from vendor's lien on property by H. Masterson to J.S. Massie S.M. Massie, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Cameron County, TX: refusal of trustee to act and appointment of substitute in deed of trust of Lon C. Hill to I.H. Kempner for benefit of H. Masterson, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Cameron County, TX: Hill Plantation Co., Gordon Hill in account with H. Masterson, 1914, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Cameron County, TX: papers re: transfer of bonds from Cameron County Irrigation District #1 to Harlingen Land Water Co., 1915 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Cameron County, TX: agreement between Robards and Henson And H. Masterson re: bonds for Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Cameron County, TX: note with collateral of Harlingen Land Water District to H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Cameron County, TX: note of Cameron County Irrigation District #1 to H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - District Courts of Harris and Cameron Counties: litigation involving debts of Lon C. Hill, but not H. Masterson, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Cameron County, TX: certified copies of deed of trust and release of Lon C. Hill to Wm. C. Craig, 1913-1914, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence re: deals with E.T. Madden, 1913-1914 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re: deals with E.T. Madden, 1915-1916 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - District Court of Cameron County, TX: certified copies of releases of liens from court judgments in suits against Lon C. Hill and Hill Sugar Co., 1918-1919 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Callahan Construction Co. re: Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1915-1917 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence re: Blakeney Maxey suit against Lon C. Hill, Jr. in Muskogee, OK, 1915-1916 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence re: Mid-Continent Building, Muskogee, OK, 1914-1916, Lon C. Hill (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Cameron County, TX: Rincon Farm matters, 1913-1914 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: Minnesota-Texas Land Irrigation Co. v. LaFeria Mutual Canal Co., 1918-1919 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: Minnesota-Texas Land Irrigation Co. v. LaFeria Mutual Canal Co., 1917 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Documents and correspondence re: Hill debts to H. Masterson, 1908, 1911-1915 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Documents and correspondence re: Hill debts to H. Masterson, 1916-1918 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re: operation of Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re: Harlingen Townsite Co., 1913-1914 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cameron Co., TX: correspondence re: Palmetal Co. and foreclosures, 1915-1916 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Cameron Co., TX: accounts of Harlingen Land Water Co. with H. Masterson, 1913-1916 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence re: sale of Harlingen Land Water Co. to Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1915-1916 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence re: operation of Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Business correspondence, Lon C. Hill, 1915-1916 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re: Harlingen Land Water Co., 1915-1916 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Gordon Hill, Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Gordon Hill, Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence re: Hill Sugar Plantation, 1913-1917 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Cameron County Irrigation District #1, Masterson guarantor, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Cameron County, TX: deed of trust and note with vendor's lien for purchase of land by Antonia Maldonado from H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Cameron County, TX: notes and deed of trust addition of John A. Hill to H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Cameron County, TX: chattel mortgage on mules of John A. Hill to H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Cameron County, TX: deeds of trust from John A. Hill to N.T. Masterson for use by H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Cameron County, TX: chattel mortgage on mules and cattle of Lon C. Hill Gordon Hill to H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Warranty deed with vendor's lien of H. Masterson to J.E. Fitch, et al, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Cameron County, TX: copy of release from vendor's lien of Tomasa N. Garza, Julian Villareal, Placido Villareal, Guadalupe de Cavazos to H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Cameron County, TX: contract between John Springer and Cameron County Irrigation District #1 for construction of flumes, April 10, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Cameron County, TX: agreement between Lon C. Hill and Gordon Hill and H. Masterson re: option to repurchase property foreclosed upon by Masterson, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Contract between Thomas F. Lee and H. Masterson re: bonds for Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Cameron County, TX: agreement between Cameron County Irrigation District #1 and W.E. Callahan Construction Co. re: construction canals and laterals, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Masterson Irrigation Co. [Cameron Co. Irrigation], 1916-1920 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Cameron County, TX dealings with Lon C. Hill and John A. Hill [Hill Sugar Co. and Mississippi Valley Trust Co.], 1911-1919 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - General correspondence, Lon C. Hill, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Lon C. Hill, 1913 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Lon C. Hill, 1911-1912 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Lon C. Hill/Rio Grande Co., 1913-1914 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Cameron Co., TX bond information re: Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1917-1919 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Cameron Co., TX bond information re: Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1910, 1915-1919 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence re: sale of bonds for Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence re: sale of bonds for Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1914-1916 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Lon C. Hill statements, 1915-1916 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Lon C. Hill statements, contracts, 1913-1916 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Harris County Irrigation District #1 returns, accounts, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Harris County Irrigation District #1 returns, accounts, 1915-1922 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Harris County Irrigation District #1 statements, reviews, 1915-1917 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Cameron County Irrigation District #1 statements, petitions, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Cameron County Irrigation District #1 statements, returns, 1915-1918 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Harlingen Land Water Co., Hill Hill Sugar Co. statements, drafts, 1913-1915 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Hill matter contracts, documents, 1912-1915 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Accounts dealing with Lon C. Hill, 1914-1917 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Accounts dealing with Lon C. Hill, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1914-1919 (1/2) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1914-1919 (2/2) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - A.C. Allen business, 1902-1904 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Richard H. Barrow, 1902-1905 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Richard H. Barrow, 1900-1908 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Richard H. Barrow, 1891, 1900-1904, 1913-1914 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Richard H. Barrow, 1902-1905 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Bartlett-Florence Railroad Co. bonds, 1910 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Brazoria County business, 1884-1885, 1894 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Brooks Supply Co., 1919 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Cravens Cage, 1915-1917 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Cravens Cage, 1906-1910 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence-Monk Palmer re: W.J. Powell Lumber lands, Leesville, La., 1906-1908 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Powell Bros. Sanders Co. Ltd; Bill of Sale of capital stock property and assets of W.H. Powell Lumber Co. to H.H. Everest by H. Masterson in settlement of debt of J.R. Sturgill, 1906— (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Farmers and Bankers Warehouse Building Association, 1906 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Farmers and Bankers Warehouse Building Association, 1906-1907 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Carter Office Bldg. Stock; Chapman Manufacturing Co. shares; Eagle Land Co., 1903, 1909, 1911 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Houstonian Publishing Co., Houston Harbor Development Co., 1906, 1916 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Proposed Houston Hotel Co. subscriptions, 1906-1907 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Interstate Mining Milling Co., CO, 1907 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Logging, 1904-1905 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Houston Transfer Carriage Co., 1909 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence re: property at Main St./Capital, Houston, 1912 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence re: property at Main St./Capital, Houston, 1912 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Masterson Sweeney, 1913-1915 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Mid Continent Life Building, Muskogee, OK, 1916-1917 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence-H. Masterson/M. Miller, 1908-1912 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence re: property of W.H. Powell and Louisiana Pecan Co., 1915-1916 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence re: property of W.H. Powell and Louisiana Pecan Co., 1916 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re: Louisiana lumber mills and land formerly owned by Powell Lumber Co., 1909-1913 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re: Louisiana lumber mills and land formerly owned by Powell Lumber Co., 1914-1917 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - W.C. Munn Co. stock; Orient Hotel, OK, 1914-1919 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Palmetal Co., 1916-1918 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Palmetal Co., 1916-1918 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Palmetal Co., 1916-1918 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Palmetal Co., 1915-1918 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Palmetal Co., 1915, 1918 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Perry family block, 1912-1918 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Perry family block, 1909-1912 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Perry family block, 1908-1912 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Perry family block, 1911-1912 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Perry family block, 1909, 1912, 1914-1915 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - W.H. Powell Lumber Co., 1906— (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - W.H. Powell Lumber Co., 1910-1911 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - W.H. Powell Lumber Co., 1910-1915 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - W.H. Powell Lumber Co., 1910 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - W.H. Powell Lumber Co., 1890s, 1900s (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - W.H. Powell Lumber Co., 1910-1911, 1913 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - W.H. Powell Lumber Co., 1909-1910 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Powell-Stanley matter, 1916-1919 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Powell Bros. Sanders Co., Ltd., 1906-1907 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Powell Bros. Sanders Co., Ltd., 1906-1909 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - McMullen Co. deed of trust of W.A. Lowe to W.T. Masterson (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence re: possible property tracks for Prince Ranch, 1908-1919 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re: possible property tracks for Prince Ranch, 1908-1919 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - McMullen Co. correspondence and papers, Prince Ranch, 1914- 1916 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - McMullen Co. correspondence and papers, Prince Ranch, 1911- 1914 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - McMullen Co. correspondence and papers, Prince Ranch, 1911- 1914 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - McMullen Co. correspondence and papers, Prince Ranch, 1906- 1910 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Atascosa, Frio, LaSalle, McMullen, re: Prince Ranch, c. 1919 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Sabine Timber lands, Vernon Parish, LA, 1911, 1914, 1916-1917 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Rockhill Country Club Co. shares, 1914 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: Rockhill Country Club, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: Rockhill Country Club, case of Nix v Withers, 1915 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: Rockhill Country Club, case of Nix v Withers, 1914 (June-Dec.) (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: Rockhill Country Club, case of Nix v Withers, 1914 (Jan-May) (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: Rockhill Country Club and J.P. Withers, 1913 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: Rockhill Country Club and J.P. Withers, 1911-1912 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Rowan Townsite Co. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Sabine Produce Irrigation Co., 1906-1907 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - South Texas Development Co., 1905-1909 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, San Antonio, Fredericksburg Northern Railway, 1916-1917 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: San Antonio, Fredericksburg and Northern Railway, 1911-1915 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Capitalization and incorporation of San Stone Mountain, 1910 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Southwestern Surety Co. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Texas Company stock, 1905-1906 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Texas-Oklahoma Investment Co. correspondence, 1915-1916 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Stock certificates of the Texas-Oklahoma Investment Co., (1-100), 1911-1914 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Stock certificates of the Texas-Oklahoma Investment Co., (101- 200), 1911-1914 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Stock certificates of the Texas-Oklahoma Investment Co., (201- 300), 1911-1914 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Texas Rubber Supply Co., 1911-1912 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Texas Rubber Supply Co. (Box 30, Folder 6)